{
    "id": "f5b9282eaaf1411f99d054d2ec2d4687",
    "title": "Future Forms Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. the doctor tomorrow.",
            "description": "The present continuous is commonly used to talk about future events which have already been planned or decided.",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "am seeing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Grandma’s train ………………………….. at 30 pm.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about time tabled future events.",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "is arriving",
                "will arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… that offer.",
            "description": "We use the simple future to talk about future events which are not already decided.",
            "answers": [
                "will accept",
                "accept",
                "am accepting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I think I ………………………. the test.",
            "description": "We use the simple future to talk about future events which are not already decided.",
            "answers": [
                "am passing",
                "will pass",
                "am going"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………….. a new home.",
            "description": "The present continuous is commonly used to talk about future events which have already been planned or decided.",
            "answers": [
                "buy",
                "are buying"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………… for Singapore tomorrow.",
            "description": "The present continuous is commonly used to talk about future events which have already been planned or decided.",
            "answers": [
                "leaves",
                "will leave",
                "is leaving"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………… here soon.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "will be",
                "be",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………. you if you touch my bag again.",
            "description": "Shall and will are common in offers, threats, promises and announcements of decisions.",
            "answers": [
                "will hit",
                "am hitting",
                "am going to hit"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………. I open the window?",
            "description": "Shall is used to ask for instructions.",
            "answers": [
                "Will",
                "Shall",
                "Would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. probably be late tonight.",
            "description": "We use the simple future to talk about future events which are not already decided.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "will",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… you a necklace.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am buying",
                "buy",
                "will buy"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Only you ……………………………. a thing like that.",
            "description": "Will can be used to criticize people.",
            "answers": [
                "are doing",
                "will do",
                "shall do"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}